- [Instructor] We are finally ready to put
the useReducer into service,
now the state is managed in a separate function,
the reducer that we have just defined right here.
And this one is in charge of returning a new state
every time that an action is dispatched.
So we're going to use the dispatch functions
to send actions to the function reducer.
Then we're going to be able to read the new
and the current state from the state objects.
And we are not going to need any more
the local state variables,
so we're going to remove them one by one.
So let's do that.
We're going to start by dispatching some actions.
So we're going to do here dispatch.
And we're going to specify the type of action
and also send a payload.
And for this one, we want to send
the information of the values,
and that corresponds to those two.
So for the type of the action,
so we're going to use the exact same
that we have defined right here,
which is used to set the values.
So let's replace here with the type of the action.
And for the values, it's going to be here random1
and random2, like this.
And we no longer need here the setValues,
so I'm going to remove it, and I'm going to remove also line 44
because this is no longer necessary, like this.
Let's do the same for this function, guessTheNumber,
that we're going to use to check the results,
and that's going to be dispatch as well.
We're going to specify a type and also a payload.
And for this one, it's going to be the results.
And for the type, let's take the one
that corresponds to checkResult.
So I'm going to take it from here and then replace right here.
And for the result, we want to send the two added together.
But remember that now we read the state
from the state object,
so we're going to do state.values.random1
+ states.values.random2, like so.
And last, we're going to remove this local state variable,
so because it's no longer necessary.
We're going to do the same for the set inputs.
So the set inputs is used inside the form.
And let me also update.
You see that now this is underlined.
We need to actually read the state from the state as well,
so this is no longer result, so I'm going to replace it.
And for the setInput,
we're going to check out inside the form components.
What we do is to get the value from the user input,
which is e.target.value.
So let's go back to App.js.
What we need is to actually get back
whatever is returned, which is value,
and it's going to be here,
we're going to dispatch from here,
and we specify a type, which is in this case setInput.
And for the payload, this will be inputs
and then value, like this.
And now you see that we have the inputs.
We no longer need the local state variable.
So I'm going to remove line 44.
And I'm going to need to update
in every place where we need to read from the state.
So let's do that. So that's going to be here as well.
For the input, it's going to be state input now.
For the result, we have already replaced
with state.results, so that's good.
So I don't think that we're missing anything.
Anyway, we're going to check this one out.
We're going to make sure that the project is up and running.
I'm going to run it with npm start.
So I'm going to open it in a new browser.
And looks like we are missing just one.
So values is not defined,
and that's because now we just read the state
from the state object.
So let's replace in the current spending lines
for the checkResult as well.
It is not defined.
Line 52, I'm going to replace, so I don't need this line.
Let me remove it.
Line 65, we need to also update,
with here, it's going to be state.values, like so.
And because we have replaced, we're using now useReducer.
We don't need to keep useStates at the top level.
So let me remove that as well.
And we're good to go.
I'm going to refresh.
I'm going to here generate random values.
Let's see if this is good.
Try again. Looks like it's not correct.
And this one you see that I am passing actually state.input.
So there was just a typo, so let me fix that.
Let's go back, let's refresh.
And this one is easy to get the right answer,
so I'm just going to input, and you guess right, excellent.
The main reasons for choosing useReducer
over useStates are multiple.
useReducer gives more control to manage the states
and allows more flexibility to handle complex state shape.
It allows to separate the business logic
from the presentation.
And so state management is more maintainable
in one separate location.
In this video, we conclude the topic
of state management with the hooks.
The things to keep in mind
is that the hooks are a simple way
to manage the state in a React project.
They make it easier than ever to create clean,
maintainable, and reusable code.
There is one common mistake you may face though,
which is to keep the state in one place
and at the top level of the application tree.
Here the logic is handled and accessible
from one single location only, line 43.
And so to pass data down to child components,
like right here, so when you need to pass data to the form
and the result components, we need to pass them manually
as props through every level of the app.
This is one recurrent issue,
commonly known as props drilling,
when you have to manually pass data
through every component from the top level to the bottom.
And so the bigger the application,
the more complex it becomes to maintain in the long run.
The best solution is to keep
the state management structure flat.
Coming next, we're going to see how to create
and handle a global state as a single source of truth.